olg.ca 2009-12-06

# OLG - Privacy Policy

Last updated: January 28, 2004. 

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please call 1-800-387-0098.

The Ontario Lottery and Gaming Corporation (OLG) is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information. This Privacy Statement explains the current information management practices at our Web sites.

The handling of all personal information by Government of Ontario organizations (including the OLG) is governed by the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FIPPA).

This Web site Privacy Policy contains detailed information about the following:

  1. What information of yours does OLG collect?
  2. How does OLG collect personal information?
  3. What are "cookies" and does OLG use them? 
  4. Who is collecting the information? 
  5. How does OLG use the information collected?
  6. Does OLG share the information that is collected?
  7. How can you access, edit or delete your information?
  8. What type of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?

This Web site Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so please check back periodically. 

External Links Disclaimer: In some cases, we link to other sites created and maintained by other public and/or private sector organizations. We provide these links solely for your information and convenience. When you link to an outside Web site, you are leaving the OLG Web site and our information management policies no longer apply. 

## 1\. What information of yours does OLG collect?

When you browse or download information from OLG Web sites, our servers automatically collect limited amounts of standard information for traffic monitoring and statistical purposes. The information is analyzed for operational trends, performance, and for ways to improve our sites. The OLG cannot identify you from this information. Example information includes, but is not limited to, the following: 

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of the computers being used to access our sites; 
  * the operating systems and the types and versions of browsers used to access our sites; 
  * the Internet Service Providers used by visitors to our sites; 
  * the dates and times users access our sites; 
  * the pages visited; and 
  * the names and sizes of files requested. 

In addition to this anonymous information, OLG may also collect information that is about an identifiable individual, referred to within as personal information. Personal information includes information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and email address. 

## 2\. How does OLG collect personal information?

Personal information is gathered when you voluntarily register within one of OLG's Web sites. This includes: 

  * submitting a comment, question or request via e-mail, 
  * requesting an e-mail alert such as Winning Numbers, 
  * entering a contest or filling out a survey online; or, 
  * requesting a product/service requiring personal information such as address, phone number, and credit card (e.g. Lotto Advance e-mail subscription request) 

In each case, any personal information you provide will be used to respond to your message and/or provide you with the requested service or product. 

Any personal information provided is collected pursuant to the Ontario Lottery and Gaming Corporation Act, 1999. For further information contact an OLG representative at 1-800-387-0098. 

## 3\. What are "cookies" and does OLG use them?

A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a Web site to the hard drive of your computer. This unique number identifies your browser, but not the individual, whenever you visit one of OLG's Web sites. These cookies will not let a Web site know any personal information about you, such as your name and address. Since these cookies are only text files, they cannot run on your computer, search your computer for other information or transmit any information to anyone. Cookies are used on many major Web sites. Many browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser either to notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies.

To help serve you better, OLG uses two types of cookies: session cookies (temporary) and persistent cookies (longer-term continuing use). Session cookies are used to support forms and registration. They are used only during your online session and expire when you close your browser. Without session cookies, moving around our Web sites would be less convenient. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive for some length of time. They are usually used if you want us to remember information about your Web preferences (e.g. language preference) and passwords for automatic log-in purposes.

## 4\. Who is collecting the information?

When you provide personal information at any OLG Web site, that information is collected by OLG. OLG may offer sweepstakes, contests or promotions on OLG Web sites. These sweepstakes, contests or promotions may be operated by third parties on behalf of OLG, in which case personal information may be collected by such third party, or disclosed to such third party by OLG. If you do not want to have OLG share your personal information for such purposes, you can choose not to opt-in to the sweepstakes, contest or promotion.

## 5\. How does the OLG use the information it collects?

Any personal information you provide to OLG when registering for products and services at any of OLG's Web sites is maintained by OLG and OLG's authorized web hosting provider, unless specifically stated otherwise. Furthermore, only certain employees of OLG have access to personal information submitted through OLG Web sites. OLG requests information from its users so that they can enjoy customized experiences across OLG Web sites. OLG may use the information it collects as follows: 

  * To offer its users the ability in the future to customize or personalize content on OLG Web sites. 
  * To deliver products and services requested by consumers. 

OLG also uses the anonymous, aggregate data to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behaviour of our Web site visitors. Without such data, it would be difficult for us to know what the most popular areas of the OLG Web sites are, and it would be difficult for us to change and update the content and services appropriately. OLG also uses such data to monitor and improve the operation of our Web sites and to maintain the quality of the products and services available through our Web sites.

If you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion through OLG's Web sites, OLG will use the personal information you provided to contact you in the event you win. All such OLG contest entry forms will provide a way for a consumer to opt-in to any communications that is not related to awarding prizes for the promotion. Any information you provide will not be shared with such third parties unless you agree through the appropriate consent box on the entry form. If you enter a contest, you may be asked, under the rules of the contest, to agree that the contest sponsor may use your name in relation to announcing and promoting the winners of the contest. OLG may disclose personal information where required by the operation of law or by a judicial or governmental body. 

## 6\. Does OLG share the information that is collected?

OLG may disclose personal information to its agents, suppliers and service providers in conjunction with providing you with products and services or operating portions of the OLG Web sites. Such entities will be required to use personal information provided solely for such purposes. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services. 

OLG does not sell, rent or lease customer lists generated through OLG Web sites to third parties. 

## 7\. How can you access, edit or delete your information?

To delete your personal information relating to the email alert functionality currently offered by OLG, please follow the unsubscribe process available through the link located at the bottom of the email. For Lotto Advance subscription requests, please use our online form to make changes to your personal information. If you would like to review your personal information for Lotto Advance subscription requests, call the OLG at 1-800-387-0098. 

## 8\. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?

OLG has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. OLG attempts to keep such information in secure facilities, protected from unauthorized access and kept only as long as is reasonably required. Only persons who have a need to know your personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy have access to the user data you choose to provide to us. OLG has imposed strict rules on OLG employees who have access to the databases that store user personal information or to the servers that host our services. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we make reasonable efforts to prevent such occurrences. OLG is not liable for any use or disclosure of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control.
